# CHRIS BORTEL

Phone: 360-580-0323 | Email: bortelcc@gmail.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://bort91.github.io/Portfolio">https://bort91.github.io/Portfolio</a>

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/christopher-bortel</u> | Github: <u>github.com/Bort91</u>

Seattle, WA 98103

## **SUMMARY**

Hard-working individual with proficiency in HTML, JavaScript, and CSS, a keen eye for detail, and the ability to communicate effectively in a team setting. Additionally, my passion for continuing education helps to further improve user experience and exceed expectations of employers as well as my friends and loved ones. Knowledgeable and effective utilizing libraries such as ReactJS.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Experience working withHTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, React; databases SQL, MongoDB; server-side development Express.js, Node.js; MERN stack development; JSON, object oriented programming; MVC frameworks; RESTful APIs, Ajax, Axios; Agile methodologies; version control and deployment on Github, Heroku; mobile responsiveness.

### **PROJECTS**

 $\label{lem:com_rel} \textbf{CribSmack} \mid \underline{\text{https://cribsmack.herokuapp.com}} \mid \underline{\text{https://cribsmack-be.herokuapp.com}} \mid \underline{\text{https://github.com/Rzavala414/Project3.git}} \mid \underline{\text{https://github.com/Rzavala414/project3-backend.git}}$ 

- MERN stack app, utilizing relational DB to create cribbage player profiles and gather user scores; renders stats to display individual stats and leaderboards of top ranked users.
- Led the production of the UI using JS, HTML, Css, ReactJS and other libraries in order to make the product easy and enjoyable to use.
- Built the logic of the game board and implemented the transfer of data to and from the database.

## SeaPoll | https://github.com/Bort91/SeaPol | https://seapoll.herokuapp.com |

A JavaScript application that utilizes Node.js, Express, Sequelize, and Axios to allow users to have individual profiles that they can use in order to stay informed on the political scene in Seattle as well as the Washington State Government.

Friend Finder | https://github.com/Bort91/FriendFinder.git | https://peaceful-spire-74053.herokuapp.com |

A friend matching application using NodeJS and Express JS to present, keep track of, and match user's based on the lowest absolute difference for all questions answered in a survey.

#### EXPERIENCE

Loyal Heights Elementary School | Seattle, WA | Special Education Instructional Assistant | Feb 2018 - Jun 2019

- Taught, advocated, built relationships, and managed a classroom of 12 students with autism and coexisting diagnosis.
- Taught students to read by breaking words down into separate sounds and then helped students "build" the words back up.
- Followed protocols and recorded behavioral and academic data with the purpose of assessing programs efficacy and make empirically based modification

Shoreline School District – Shoreline, WA | *District Behavior Support Para-Professional* | *Aug 2017 – Nov 2017* Seattle Behavior Consulting and Therapy – Seattle, WA | *Registered Behavior Technician* | *Aug 2016 – Aug 2017* Jane Addams Middle School | Seattle, WA | *Special Education Assistant* | *March 2014 – June 2016* 

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Washington Coding Bootcamp - Seattle, WA | Full Stack Developer | Graduated Nov 2019 Pacific Lutheran University - Tacoma, WA | *BA* | Psychology; Chinese Studies | Graduated Dec 2013 Beijing Foreign Studies University - China | *August 2011 - May 2012*